<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.victoralvesf.aonsoku</id>

  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <name>Aonsoku</name>
  <summary>A modern desktop client for Navidrome/Subsonic servers</summary>

  <developer id="io.github.victoralves">
    <name>Victor Alves</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <ul>
      <li><em>Subsonic Integration:</em> Aonsoku integrates with your Navidrome or Subsonic server, providing you with easy access to your music collection.</li>
      <li><em>Intuitive UI:</em> Modern, clean and user-friendly interface designed to enhance your music listening experience.</li>
      <li><em>Podcast Support:</em> With Aonsoku Podcasts you can easily access, manage, and listen to your favorites podcasts directly within the app. Enjoy advanced search options, customizable filters and seamless listening synchronization to enhance your podcast experience.</li>
      <li><em>Synchronized lyrics:</em> Aonsoku will automatically find a synced lyric from LRCLIB if none is provided by the server.</li>
      <li><em>Unsynchronized lyrics:</em> If your songs have embedded unsynchronized lyrics, Aonsoku is able to show them.</li>
      <li><em>Radio:</em> If your server supports it, listen to radio shows directly within Aonsoku.</li>
      <li><em>Scrobble:</em> Sync played songs with your server.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.victoralvesf.aonsoku.desktop</launchable>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <url type="homepage">https://aonsoku.vercel.app</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/victoralvesf/aonsoku</url>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/victoralvesf/aonsoku/e5cb4546f2f874fd24c25045882c908b8032e728/media/home.png</image>
      <caption>Home page</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/victoralvesf/aonsoku/e5cb4546f2f874fd24c25045882c908b8032e728/media/playlist.png</image>
      <caption>Playlist</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/victoralvesf/aonsoku/e5cb4546f2f874fd24c25045882c908b8032e728/media/artist.png</image>
      <caption>Artist view</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.11.0" date="2025-12-14">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/victoralvesf/aonsoku/releases/tag/v0.10.2</url>
      <description>
        <p>New Features</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Subdirectory Deployment: Updated the Vite base URL to support deploying the application within subdirectories.</li>
          <li>Favorite Songs: Added a "Favorite Songs" section to the Sidebar. </li>
          <li>Open Subsonic Synced Lyrics: Added synced lyrics support for OpenSubsonic API-compatible servers.</li>
          <li>Big Player Animation: Enhanced the fullscreen transition animation for the Big Player.</li>
          <li>Big Player Trigger: Relocated the Big Player open button to the main player controls (previously on cover art hover).</li>
          <li>Enhanced Song Info: Added detailed audio metadata to the quality badge in the songs table.</li>
          <li>Shortcut Keys UI: Redesigned the keyboard shortcuts component for better readability.</li>
          <li>Image Caching: Introduced an Image Caching option in Content Settings to improve loading times and overall performance.</li>
          <li>Reduced App Minimum Size: Reduced the application's minimum window dimensions to better support vertical monitors and tiling window managers.</li>
          <li>Localization: Added new languages and expanded coverage for existing translations.</li>
          <li>Custom LRCLIB Instances: Added an option in Privacy Settings to configure custom self-hosted or private LRCLIB URLs.</li>
          <li>Playlist Visibility Icons: Updated the icons used to distinguish between public and private playlists</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Empty State Layout: Fixed an issue where empty state spacing caused unnecessary page scrolling.</li>
          <li>Sidebar Interaction: Disabled the sidebar toggle button when the Queue or Lyrics panels are open.</li>
          <li>Security Updates: Updated project dependencies to address security vulnerabilities.</li>
          <li>Playlist Management: Fixed an issue preventing users from clearing playlist comments/descriptions.</li>
          <li>Sample Rate Display: Corrected the sample rate label display.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.2" date="2025-12-14">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/victoralvesf/aonsoku/releases/tag/v0.10.2</url>
      <description>
        <p>New Features</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Dynamic Sidebar: Added a toggle to resize the sidebar width.</li>
          <li>Discord Rich Presence: Added support to share the currently playing song via Discord Rich Presence.</li>
          <li>Minimize to Tray: Added support for minimizing the app to the system tray with accessible player controls.</li>
          <li>About Dialog: Improved the styling of the "About" information dialog.</li>
          <li>New Languages: Added support for Canadian French, Italian, Korean, Malay, Polish, Turkish, and Ukrainian.</li>
          <li>Sync Lyrics Cache: Implemented a persistent cache layer for synced lyrics to improve performance on subsequent requests.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Security: Fixed an XSS vulnerability in the sanitization function.</li>
          <li>UI: Fixed shadow rendering for Album, Playlist, and Artist titles.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>